

# AYISHA SHIHARA RIHAM SOWKATHALI

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

### **ABOUT**

Software developer with robust problem-solving skills and proven experience in designing, developing, and implementing software in a testdriven environment. Excellent communication, problem solving and programming skills. Selfsufficient, flexible, and a good team player. Familiar working with both large and small team environments. Self-motivated and quick learner of new concepts and technologies.

### CONTACT



Block 77 Lorong Limau #05-43 Singapore 320077



+65 9161 9753



ayishasr.sowkathali@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/ayishasowkathali

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

International Business Management Institute Mini MBA, 2021

Credential ID: 325421-163-891-1264

International Business Management Institute Innovation Management, 2020 Credential ID: 325421-160-050-2306

## **CAREER SUMMARY**

Feb 2019 - Jan 2020 Associate Software Developer | Full Time | Sogeti, USA

Mar 2018 - Dec 2018 Front End Developer | Remote Work | Acsys International, India

May 2017 - Jan 2018 Front End Developer | Remote Work | Intramed, India

### **EDUCATION**

Texas State University, San Marcos, TX Bachelor of Science, 2018 Majored in Computer Science Minored in Mathematics

Austin Community College, Austin, TX Associate of Science, 2014 Majored in General Science

Austin Peace Academy, Austin, TX High School Diploma, 2012

# **SKILLS**

#### Frontend Languages

- HTML5, CSS3, CSS Preprocessors, JavaScript, Angular, ReactJS, VueJS jQuery Data Tables, Bootstrap, AJAX

### **Backend Languages**

- C++, Java, JavaScript, C# .Net, Python, Scala, PHP, Ruby

#### **Database Languages**

- MySQL, MongoDB, Oracle, SQL Server, SQL Server, PostgreSQL

#### **Operating System**

- MacOS, Windows10, Linux/UNIX, Ubuntu, Debian GNU, CentOS

## **Developing Platforms**

- IntelliJ IDEA, Eclipse, NetBeans, XCode, Atom, Sublime Text, Mac Terminal
- MS Visual Studio, MS Visio, MS InfoPath 2007
- MySQL Work Bench, Harvest
- HP Quality Center, HP Performance Center
- Microsoft Azure

## Tools / Technologies

- GIT, SOAP UI, GIT Extensions, GitHub Continuous Integration Cruise Control
- Continuous Integration using TeamCity
- Selenium and Automation, WCF services / Rest services
- SAAS, SEO
- Deployment using Octopus, Grunt, NPM, Bower, HTTP, REST
- Figma, Adobe Photoshop
- Waterfall Methodologies, Agile & Scrum Methodologies
- Travis CI, Hudson, Jenkins, TeamCity, GitLab

#### Soft Skills

- Problem-solving skills and critical thinking.
- Excellent Communication Skills.
- Teamwork and collaboration
- Self-Confident, and Resilient
- Management (people, time, and project)
- Accountability
- Multi-Tasking
- Decision Making
- Organized
- Adaptability and flexibility
- Open-minded
- Ability to accept feedback

# **WORK EXPERIENCES**

Associate Software Developer | Sogeti, USA Feb 2019 – Jan 2020

Project: Merch API for China Home

# Description:

This project is to design a merchandise interface for shopping for home appliances. The project was created using standard web development techniques to provide a user-friendly interface for both mobile and web.

### Responsibilities:

- Understood each Story card and developed the feature based on each iteration
- Contributed fully to design assessments, code reviews, and brainstorming sessions
- Gained experience in software development, testing software, and quality assurance for software
- Gained knowledge about Selenium and Automation, WCF services / Rest services.
- Coordinated with all team projects and monitor all product life cycles and prepare all specifications and perform tests on all configurations and installations.
- Performed high-quality unit tests on all software as per Quality assurance programs and maintain knowledge of all latest technology and prepared various codes based on software designs.
- Closely worked with business in Requirements Analysis, Pre-scoping, Data profiling, and Prototyping activities to understand the requirements and system design.
- Performed fix issues and troubleshooting in production support.
- Done software development, testing, and deployment of components of various modules of the project.
- Responsible for the support of the full application after the successful deployment.
- Analyzed and identified all issues in requirements and design and assisted to provide resolution of same and performed various tests on software to resolve all issues.
- Provide internal support for all products and assist various departments.
- Performed tests on software and provided resolution and coordinated with software engineers to ensure efficiency in the implementation of all software.
- Performed troubleshooting on all programs to ensure compliance with deadlines and collaborated with Quality Assurance tests to perform end-to-end tests.
- Expert in fulfillment of data warehouse project tasks such as Planning, Requirement gathering, identifying sources, and execution of projects including the planning of implementation activities.
- Coordinated with all cross-functional teams to analyze all issues.
- Worked in both Waterfall and Agile/SRCUM methodologies
- Managed schedule of sub-system and participated in formulation and analysis of system development life cycle.
- Documented unit test procedures and participated in the software development process to perform all tests on designs and ensure compliance with all Object-Oriented Programming activities.

# **WORK FXPFRIFNCES**

Front End Developer | Acsys International, India Mar 2018 - Dec 2018

# Project: Specialized Telecommunications Assistance Program (STAP)

### **Description:**

Consultant for multiple vendors working in partnership. Projects included upgrading to a new booking reservation system, integrating a reservation system with multiple vendors for price matching, best route matching, matching algorithm for matching search criteria and search results for best deals, alternative routes/options, etc.

### Responsibilities:

- Understood each requirement and developed the functionalities based on Requirement Design Document.
- Understanding of key website design principles and SEO optimization
- Used client input to create functional, creative, and user-friendly webpages
- Strongly followed the agile development methodology in the project using Visual Studio Team foundation server 2015
- Developed Web pages using AngularJS, HTML5, and Bootstrap3 to support a mobile-first approach.
- Involved in preparing documentation for Release readiness and schedule for production.
- Participated in meeting such as Release Planning, Business Requirement Gathering Meeting, Daily Team Meeting, External Team interaction for Deployment, Process flow review, and Monthly Retrospective.
- Involved in developing client-side grid using jQuery, Bootstrap & HTML5.
- Worked with clients to develop the overall look and design of a website
- Wrote website code with programming languages such as HTML, C++, and Java
- Produced, maintained, and modified websites and user interfaces
- Incorporated applications, graphics, audio, and video clips into client websites
- Created tools that enhance the user's website experience
- Ensured websites are accessible across many platforms, including laptops and smartphones
- Routinely tested websites for ease of use, speed, and other quality factors
- Fixed any website issues or bugs that arise
- Was involved in designing and developing the User Interface
- Worked with Indexes and Views for Database tuning.
- Performed Knowledge transfer and training to various customers, admins, and other groups.
- Several existing Components are modified as per the requirement.
- Optimized our web application for maximum speed.
- Did Testing: Unit testing and Integration testing and was responsible for communicating projects related to a client.
- Experienced with responsive and adaptive design.

# **WORK EXPERIENCES**

## Front End Developer | IntraMed, India May 2017 – Jan 2018

# Project: Compliant online learning management system

### **Description:**

IntraMed is to facilitate the transformation of quality care in medicine by innovating scalable Internet technologies and related services that support the continuing medical education, professional development, and performance improvement needs of stakeholders in the healthcare paradigm to positively impact and measure changes in practice behavior, patient care, and outcomes.

# Responsibilities:

- Understood each Story card and developed the feature based on each iteration
- Determined the structure and design of web pages.
- Ensured user experience determines design choices.
- Developed features to enhance the user experience.
- Maintained a balance between functional and aesthetic design.
- Ensured web design is optimized for smartphones.
- Built reusable code for future use.
- Optimized web pages for maximum speed and scalability.
- Utilized a variety of markup languages to write web pages.
- Maintained brand consistency throughout the design.
- Used GIT Extensions as Source control for document management
- Coordination with Business Team and Testing Team for Defect Fixing.
- Show & tell with Businesspeople for each iteration
- Attended the grooming session for major features with the Business team
- Provided technical specifications for the tasks and implemented them as per suggestions.
- Worked with Back-End Developers to ensure all pages work according to briefs
- Changed design and content of existing pages for the benefit of users, clients, and colleagues
- Worked alongside colleagues and other stakeholders to ensure speed and stability of the user experience
- Understood the needs of the company and worked with relevant personnel to ensure maximum effectiveness of web pages
- Understood the SEO principles.
- Good problem-solving skills.
- Excellent verbal communication skills.
- Good interpersonal skills.